Guide to the Cornell University calendar collection, 1902-2005.
Cornell University calendar collection,
- Series I. Chronological list of calendars
  - Cornell 1934, 1934 (Box 3)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); features a photograph of "President Farrand addressing the Class of 1933" in June; also includes one aerial-view photograph of the campus.
  - Cornell 1934, 1934 (Box 3)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement), with one photograph of "The Junior Prom" (in February) and one of "President Farrand addressing the Class of 1933" (in June); also includes two aerial-view photographs of the campus (in April).
  - Cornell 1935, 1935 (Box 3)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); also includes one aerial-view photograph of the "College of Agriculture."
  - Cornell 1936, 1936 (Box 3)
    "#2070-" handwritten in pencil in top left corner of cover; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); "Jack Batten" and "Jeff Stofer" are featured in football photographs in November; also includes one aerial-view photograph of the campus.
  - Cornell 1937, 1937 (Box 3)
    "#2070-" handwritten in pencil in top left corner of cover; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); also includes two aerial-view photographs of the campus.
  - Cornell 1938, 1938 (Box 4)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and several events (e.g. sports and commencement); also includes three aerial-view photographs of the campus.
  - Cornell 1939, 1939 (Box 4)
    The cover features the Cornell shield; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; most of the photographs for this calendar are loose (though all are present); the photograph of the "Interior View of Willard Straight Hall" for the month of March is unique.
  - Cornell 1940, 1940 (Box 4)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; unfortunately, photographs are missing for the months of January, February, April, July, October, and December; the leaf for the month of August is stuck to the back of July with the adhesive used for the photographs; a unique, solemn-looking (taken during the "Pledge of Allegiance" or some other song or prayer [?]) photograph of "Commencement" is featured for June.
  - Cornell 1941, 1941 (Box 4)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; a scenic photograph of the "Willard Straight Rock Garden" is featured for June.
  - Cornell 1942, 1942 (Box 4)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; the month of May features an uncommon (and somewhat perspectiveless) photograph of "Cayuga Lake from Stewart Avenue Bridge;" a BW illustration of the "Entrance to Balch Hall at Night" is depicted for December.
  - Cornell 1943, 1943 (Box 4)
    The cover features a colored-in photograph of the R.O.T.C. ensigns marching in formation, as seen from a window in the Cornell War Memorial; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus and two events (i.e. one untitled event at the "Cornell War Memorial" in May and "Senior Singing" in June).
  - Cornell 1944, 1944 (Box 4)
    Comes with the original 1944 envelope; features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; for the month of July, the "Ensigns Training at Cornell" can be seen standing in formation by the Cornell War Memorial; and, again, in December, the same BW illustration of the "Entrance to Balch Hall at Night" is featured with the addition of Christmas lights on the conifer, front-and-center.
  - Cornell 1946, 1946 (Box 4)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus; the picture for June offers "A Glimpse of 'Collegetown'" (at approximately the intersection of Williams St., Eddy St., and Dryden Rd. ) in 1946.
  - Cornell 1947, 1947 (Box 4)
    Features BW photographs (with titles underneath) of the Cornell campus.
  - Cornell engagement calendar, 1947, 1947 (Box 4)
    Weekly engagement calendar, with black and white photographs of campus buildings and activities. No annotations, but last page is stamped: The Triangle Book Shop, Evan J. Morris, Prop., Sheldon Court, Ithaca, New York.
  - The Cornell Calendar 1956-57, 1956-1957 (Box 5)
    Academic calendar with many black and white photos. Includes listings for athletic activities, concerts, and other events. Annotated by previous owner.
  - The Cornell Calendar 1957-58, 1957-1958 (Box 5)
  - The Cornell Calendar 1958-59, 1958-1959 (Box 5)
  - The Cornell Calendar 1959-60, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - The Cornell Calendar 1960-61, 1960-1961 (Box 5)
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1976-1977, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1976 to July 1977; the calendar offers general information relevant to student-life (e.g. information about the "Academic Program" and class-times and final examinations for September and October); none of the BW photographs are titled or credited; the back of the calendar includes publication credits and a list of important academic and support service phone numbers. Annotated by previous owner.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1977-1978, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1977 to August 1978; the calendar offers general information relevant to student-life (e.g. information about the "Academic Program" and class-times and final examinations for September and October); none of the BW photographs are titled or credited; the back of the calendar includes publication credits and a list of important academic and support service phone numbers.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1978-1979, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1978 to July 1979; the calendar offers general information relevant to student-life (e.g. information about the "Academic Program" and class-times and final examinations for September and October); none of the BW photographs are titled or credited; the back of the calendar includes publication credits and a list of important academic and support service phone numbers.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1979-1980, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1979 to September 1980; the calendar offers general information relevant to student-life (e.g. information about the "Academic Program" and class-times and final examinations for September and October); none of the BW photographs are titled or credited; the back of the calendar includes publication credits and a list of important academic and support service phone numbers.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1983-1984, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1983 to August 1984; the calendar offers general information relevant to student-life (e.g. information about the "Academic Program" and class-times and final examinations for October and November); the cover of the calendar features a four-paragraph history of the original Cornell mascot, Touchdown, a flesh-and-blood bear; the back of the calendar includes publication credits and a list of important academic and support service phone numbers.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1984-1985, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1984 to August 1985; the calendar offers general information relevant to student-life (e.g. information about the "Academic Program" and class-times and final examinations for October and November); the BW photographs featured (and captioned!) actually date back to the earlier decades of Cornell (only one photograph is dated [at 1875]) and possess historical interest; the back of the calendar includes publication credits and a list of important academic and support service phone numbers.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1985-1986, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1985 to August 1986; the calendar offers general information relevant to student-life (e.g. information about the "Academic Program" and class-times and final examinations for October and November); none of the BW photographs are titled or credited; the back of the calendar includes publication credits and a list of important academic and support service phone numbers.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1986-1987, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1986 to August 1987; the calendar offers general information relevant to student-life (e.g. information about the "Academic Program" and class-times and final examinations for October and November); there is a handwritten note in ink on the month of November next to a photograph of John L. Ford, previous Dean of Students at Cornell, reading: "My / old poker / buddy John / Ford! / T.H.;" none of the BW photographs are titled or credited; the back of the calendar includes publication credits and a list of important academic and support service phone numbers.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1988-1989, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1988 to August 1989; the theme of this calendar is "Tap into the Cultural Life of Cornell University" and the BW photographs therein showcase the music, theater, and dance exhibitions at Cornell; the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 1988 to 1989 in brief; the final leaf of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 1989 Cornell Calendar, 1989 (Box 5)
    The cover features a view of central campus with the distant lights of Ithaca shining in the night sky; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus and include paragraph-long descriptions; the end of the calendar shows a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years (there are no image or publishing credits on the calendar); on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1989-1990, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1989 to August 1990; the theme of this calendar is "Treasure Hunt for Campus Sites" wherein 15 locations throughout the Cornell campus are photographed and hinted at (e.g. in January, "This hilltop facility is known for its oriental rugs. The bronze tablet on its fireplace commemorates a visit by President Ulysses S. Grant."--the answer is A.D. White House.); those who could answer the 15 locations correctly could win a $50 Campus Store gift certificate; the last page of the calendar includes both the contest rules and the publication credits.
  - 1990 Cornell Calendar, 1990 (Box 5)
    The cover features the Arts Quad on a partly-sunny day in Ithaca; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus; the photograph for March shows a scene from the Dragon Day 1989 Parade; also, for the month of November, there is a unique photograph of "Big Red fans--and their umbrellas--in Shoellkopf Stadium;" the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1990-1991, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1990 to August 1991; the theme of this calendar is "Treasure Hunt for Campus Sites" wherein 12 locations throughout the Cornell campus are photographed and hinted at (e.g. in February, "People in this place think about how the world shifts as the millennia unfold."--the answer is Snee Hall); those who could answer the 12 locations correctly could win a $50 Campus Store gift certificate (note: this calendar is much easier than the 1989-1990 challenge); the last page of the calendar includes both the contest rules and the publication credits.
  - 1991 Cornell Calendar, 1991 (Box 5)
    The cover features the frequently-photographed-but-ah!-it-is-spring! "McGraw Tower, graced by tulip magnolia blossoms;" the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus; the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - 1992 Cornell Calendar, 1992 (Box 5)
    The cover features "A view of the campus from West Hill;" the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus; the photograph for May is of the "Johnson Graduate School of Management graduates celebrating" by wildly flinging handfuls of fake US dollars into the air like confetti; the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1992-1993, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1992 to July 1993; the month of October features a BW photograph of students, from the Interfraternity Council and the Panhellenic Association, tossing ground beef into what looks like an enormous raised garden bed but what is in fact the largest lasagna in America as part of a fund-raiser for Ithaca's Southside Community Center; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 1993 Cornell Calendar, 1993 (Box 5)
    The cover features McGraw Tower at night, the moon in its third-quarter ghostly in the violet sky; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus; the photograph for July shows "Dedication ceremonies for Akwe:kon, the Native American residential program house;" the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell 1993 Calendar, 1993 (Box 5)
    A January to December calendar featuring hand-illustrated BW drawings of many buildings on campus; the first leaf opens to a list of 18 drawings not included with the months; the final leaf includes a BW map of the campus with a key for the location of the buildings; the calendar and the drawings are by Ioana Schipor.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1993-1994, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1993 to July 1994; the month of November features a BW photograph of director Spike Lee (with blurb about the Cornell University Program Board and its speakers); the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 1994 Cornell Calendar, 1994 (Box 5)
    The cover features Myron Taylor Hall; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus; the photograph for March features "[t]he ritual burning of the first-year architecture students' dragon" (the year of the parade, however, is uncredited); the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1994-1995, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1994 to August 1995; the month of March features a BW photograph of the Dragon Day Parade (the year of the parade, however, is uncredited) with a short history included; the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 1994 to 1995 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 1995 Cornell Calendar, 1995 (Box 5)
    The cover features McGraw Tower at sundown; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus; the photograph for February is unique, featuring "Ice Hockey in Lynah Rink;" the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1995-1996, 1995-1996 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1995 to August 1996; the theme of this calendar is "The [Willard] Straight's 70th Anniversary" and, to complement, it includes confetti, photographs and short histories of the construction of the building in addition to its many renovations and notable programs throughout the decades (e.g. the month of September features the original floor plan of Willard Straight Hall and a photograph of "The Cornerstone Laying Ceremony, June 15, 1924"); the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 1995 to 1996 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 1996 Cornell Calendar, 1996 (Box 5)
    The cover features "Sibley Hall and Dome" with a bicyclist riding past; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to the Cornell campus; the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1996-1997, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1996 to August 1997; the theme of this calendar is "Exploring Cornell" and, to complement, it includes "Did you know that ..." facts about the various buildings on campus (e.g. in February, "Did you know that ... the opening in the middle of the Johnson Museum building lets the afternoon sunlight reach the Arts Quad?"); the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 1996 to 1997 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1997-1998, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that covers the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1997 to August 1998; the theme of this calendar is "Windows of Opportunity, Windows to the World" and, to complement, it includes many quotes to inspire optimism in uncertainty (e.g. for the month of February, "Daring ideas are like chessman moved forward; they may be beaten, but they may start winning a game. --Johann Wolfgang von Goethe, German writer and dramatist);" the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 1997 to 1998 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 1998 Cornell Calendar, 1998 (Box 5)
    The cover features the "Sackett Bridge on Beebe Lake-Fall Creek;" the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to major events (such as commencement) to the Cornell campus; the month of March shows a scene of the Dragon Day 1997 Parade; the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1998-1999, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that documents the Cornell's Department of Natural Resources celebration (in 1998) of the 100-year anniversary of the College of Forestry and the 50-year anniversary of the Department of Conservation, in addition to covering the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1998 to August 1999; features BW photographs taken throughout the years at the Department of Natural Resources and its many notable affiliates and research (e.g. the feature for February contrasts the technology of "yesterday" via a photograph the enormous sampling gear to record bird songs with the supercomputers of "today"); the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 1998 to 1999 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 1999 Cornell Calendar, 1999 (Box 5)
    The cover features "The Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art" at twilight; the large color photographs feature a wide variety of subjects from infamous Ithaca weather to student life to major events (such as commencement) to the Cornell campus; the end of the calendar shows the image and publishing credits in addition to a calendar in brief of the previous and the following years; on the very back of the calendar is a short history of Cornell University.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 1999-2000, 1999-2000 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that showcases the many "Gifts, Gardens, and Memorials" found around the Cornell campus in addition to covering the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 1999 to August 2000; features BW photographs of the more (and a few of the less) known memorials on the Cornell campus with short histories included (e.g. the month of February features the sculptor Jason Seley '40 and his Herakles in Ithaka I, presented in 1982 and installed next to the Statler Hotel where it can still be found at present); the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 1999 to 2000 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - Cornell Academic-Year Calendar 2000-2001, 2000-2001 (Box 5)
    An academic-year calendar that celebrates the 100-year history of "The College of Human Ecology" in addition to covering the many academic, sports, and extracurricular events on campus from August 2000 to August 2001; features BW photographs taken throughout the years at the College of Human Ecology and its many affiliates and research (e.g. in September, three photographs demonstrating the wide range of disciplines in the Human Ecology program with a two-paragraph description and captions); the end of the calendar features the academic-year of 2000 to 2001 in brief; the back of the calendar includes publication credits.
  - 2001 Cornell Calendar, 2001 (Box 5)